dapper.net 2010-12-29

# Dapper Privacy Policy

Last Updated: Oct 13, 2010

**Privacy Policy**

On October 13th 2010, Dapper was acquired by Yahoo!. User information collected by Dapper continues to be subject to the Dapper Privacy Policy. In the future, you may be asked to link your current Dapper information to an existing or new Yahoo! ID. At that point, the [Yahoo! Privacy Policy](http://info.yahoo.com/privacy/) will apply to all information associated with your Dapper account. 

DAPPER Inc., (in this policy: "we", "us", or "our") cares about your privacy. This policy explains the accepted privacy practices for our website at www.dapper.net ("Dapper").

This policy covers, among other things, what personal information we collect from you whether you are a registered user or not, how we use and disclose your personal information and the data obtained automatically when you use Dapper or its services, and how we retain it. Section I describes how we collect, use, and disclose data from users and visitors to Dapper.net.  Section II describes how we collect, use, and disclose information from users who simply view a Dapper Ad published on a third party web site.  Section III describes our data security and retention policy, and Section IV describes our commitment to children’s privacy.

If you have any questions or concerns about this policy or our information practices, please contact us at info@dapper.net.

We may change the terms of this Policy from time to time, in which case, we will post a notice on Dapper that the policy has been changed, and update the “last updated” date to reflect the date of the latest modifications. If you are a registered user, we will attempt to notify you using the email address you provided when you registered.  We recommend that you read this policy periodically to keep informed about our data collection, use, and disclosure practices.  We will not, without your consent, use information previously collected from you in a manner inconsistent with the terms of the policy in place when it was collected.

**I.          _YOUR USE OF DAPPER.NET_**

**_Personal Information we collect_**

When you register with Dapper we may ask you to provide personal details such as your name and e-mail address. You will also be asked to provide us with a username and password.

The fields for compulsory completion will be explicitly indicated. If you do not enter the requisite data in these fields, you will be unable to register with Dapper. 

We may collect further information when you use Dapper. For example, we may record the frequency and scope of your use of Dapper, the duration of your sessions, Dapps that you use or create, advertisement that you click on, the Internet protocol (IP) address that serves you to access Dapper and the geographic location from where you logged-in. We automatically gather this information, through the use of log files. If you are registered with Dapper, the information we gather may be anonymous or in some instances personally identifiable, and it may be associated with other personally identifiable information you have provided us. If you are not a registered user, yet accessed the site, we will not knowingly collect any information which may personally identify you.

Further information may be collected when we exchange communications with you, or when our designated copyright agent is in contact with you with respect to your content on Dapper.

**_Usernames and passwords to other websites_**

Some web pages have a login form. If you submit the form through Dapper, we will pass your username and password to the remote website, using the level of security that the remote website allows. Dapper will not store your username or password or share it with others. As a result, you will have to enter your username and password whenever you use the Dapp you are creating. However, in some instances we may have to store your username and password. For example, when you create an alert based on a Dapp we must periodically check the content related to your Dapp, without your intervention. In such cases, we will take measures to protect the information in order to minimize the risk of its exposure to unauthorized third parties.

**_How do we use your personal information?_**

We will use personally identifiable information for the following purposes:

  * To enable you to use Dapper, including the Dapps that you create, store, transmit or otherwise distribute when using Dapper; 

  * To post your Dapps on Dapper;

  * To allow you to access and use saved Dapps on Dapper and to adjust Dapper to your personal preferences; 

  * To facilitate the display of information and advertisements pertaining to products and services which might interest you; 

  * To provide you from time to time with information pertaining to Dapper;

  * To contact you as and when we believe it to be necessary;

  * Subject to your express consent at the time of registration with Dapper or later, to send you, from time to time, information pertaining to our services, as well as marketing and advertising material, whether ours or others'. You may withdraw your consent at any time and cease receiving material of this kind, by following the relevant procedure at Dapper. In any case, we will not share your personal details with any advertisers, without your explicit consent.

  * To any other purpose, as stipulated in this Policy, or in the Terms of Use governing the use of Dapper ("Terms of Use").

We may use anonymous information for the proper operation and function of Dapper, to improve the quality of Dapper and to enhance your experience, to create new services, including services tailored to users’ personal requirements and expectations, and to change or cancel existing features and content. We may share such information with others, provided that it does not identify you personally. 

**_Sharing and disclosing information_**

We may share personally identifiable information with others in any of the following instances.

  * If we reasonably believe that you have breached the Terms of Use or abused Dapper; 
  * If by using Dapper, you perform or attempt to perform any activity which we may reasonably believe to be illegal; 
  * If we are required by law to do so; 
  * In any case of dispute, or legal proceeding of any kind between Us and you; 
  * In any case where we may reasonably believe that sharing information is necessary to prevent damage; 
  * When we engage a third party consultant or service provider to assist in development, maintenance, and hosting of Dapper; and 
  * In connection with a corporate reorganization, or if we are acquired by, or merged with another entity, provided, however, that those entities agree to be bound by the provisions of this policy.

We may also share personal information with companies or organizations connected, or affiliated with us, such as subsidiaries and parent companies, with the express provision that their use of such information must comply with this Privacy Policy;

**_Cookies_**

Cookies are packets of information sent by our servers to your web browser and then sent back by the browser each time it accesses our servers. Dapper utilizes cookies and in order to use the service you must enable cookies in your web browser.

Our cookies may contain a variety of information, such as the Dapps you have accessed, session durations and IP addresses. We may also use cookies to save you the need to re-enter your user name and password each time you log-in on Dapper. 

We may use cookies for various purposes, such as to facilitate the use of Dapper, to collect statistical information about the use of Dapper, to verify information, to adjust Dapper to your personal preferences and for information security purposes. 

Some of the Cookies may expire when the session ends and you exit your browser. Other cookies are saved on your computer’s hard drive. If you wish to block our cookies, you may do so by clicking the "options" button on your browser's menu and follow the necessary instructions. You can read your browser's Help file of for further information. However, bear in mind that disabling cookies may complicate or even prevent the use of Dapper, or certain features thereof. 

**_Third Party Advertising Displayed on Dapper.net_**

We may permit other companies to conduct advertising campaigns on Dapper. The advertisements that you will be exposed to at Dapper are redirected from the servers of those advertising companies. Some advertisers may store and use cookies on your computer. The cookies enable them to collect information about websites that you have accessed, advertisements posted on those sites and the advertisements that you have viewed. In this manner advertisers try to display advertisements tailored to your preferences. The use made by the advertisers of cookies is subject to their own privacy policies and not to this Policy. If you wish to study the privacy policies of those advertisers you should visit their websites, or contact them directly.

**II.        _DAPPER’S ADVERTISING SERVICE_**

Dapper provides an advertising service through which we deliver ads and other promotions of our advertiser customers to third party publishers’ web sites (“Dapper Ads”). 

**_Information we collect_**

In connection with our advertising service, we do not knowingly collect any information which may personally identify you, or associate the information we do collect with any personally identifiable information about you that we may have in our system as a result of the collection mechanisms discussed in Section I, above.

_Cookies_ :  When you browse a web site that includes a Dapper Ad, belongs to one of our advertiser customers, one of our advertiser’s partners, or one of our data partners and their affiliates, we use a “web beacon” (a small string of code embedded in the publisher’s web site that connects directly to Dapper’s systems), to store and retrieve cookies on your computer or device.  We store information in cookies about your browsing activity and preferences, including the addresses or names of websites with our web beacon or Dapper Ads that you have accessed, the content you viewed on those website, searches you performed on those websites, Dapper Ads displayed on the web , the Dapper Ads that you have viewed and/or clicked on, and the date, time, and duration of your visits.  If you clear your cookies, we will no longer have access to that information the next time you visit a site that displays a Dapper Ad.  Dapper cookies are generally set to expire 180 days after being set.

_Log Files_ :  We collect and store certain technical information in our log files, such as your IP address, device and browser type, the date and time of your visit, web pages you viewed, searches you performed, the search you may have used to find the particular site displaying the Dapper Ad, the web page you viewed before coming to the site displaying the Dapper Ad.

_Forms_ :  Certain Dapper Ads may contain mechanisms for you to submit information, such as through a form.  The information you provide in any such form is submitted directly to the third party advertiser, subject to that third party advertiser’s policies on information collection, use, and disclosure.  Dapper is not involved in any such form submission, and does not receive or collect any information submitted in this manner.

**_How do we use your information?_**

We use the information we collect from you through our advertising service for a variety of purposes.  Cookie information is used to better understand your browsing habits and interests, so that we can tailor ad content displayed to you when you browse any of the third party publishers’ web sites that display Dapper Ads.  We may use anonymous information, such as the information we collect through cookies and log files, for the proper operation and function of Dapper, to improve the quality of Dapper and to enhance your experience, to create new services, including services tailored to users’ personal requirements and expectations, and to change or cancel existing features and content.

**_Sharing and disclosing information_**

We may share information we collect in connection with our advertising service with others in any of the following instances: 

  * If we are required by law to do so; 
  * In any case of dispute, or legal proceeding of any kind between us and you; 
  * In any case where we may reasonably believe that sharing information is necessary to prevent damage; 
  * When we engage a third party consultant or service provider to assist in development, maintenance, and hosting of Dapper or the Dapper advertising service and to perform other related business functions on our behalf; and 
  * In connection with a corporate reorganization, or if we are acquired by, or merged with another entity, provided, however, that those entities agree to be bound by the provisions of this policy. 

We may also provide our third party advertiser customers with anonymous and aggregated information we collect in connection with display of their ads through our advertising service.

**_Opting Out_**

If you prefer not to allow Dapper to collect information about your browsing patterns through the use of cookies, you can opt out by clicking this link.  When you opt out, we clear your existing Dapper Ads cookies and set a cookie on your computer or device that identifies to us that you have opted out.  If you subsequently clear or block your cookies, Dapper will no longer be able to determine that you have opted out and will begin setting cookies on your computer or device again.  You may also update your browser’s settings to decline cookies altogether, which will prevent Dapper from using cookies to collect and store your information. You can learn more about opt out and opt out from our partners' targeting by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative opt out page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).

**III.       _INFORMATION SECURITY AND RETENTION_**

We implement systems, applications and procedures to secure your personal information, to minimize the risks of theft, damage, loss of information, or unauthorized access or use of information. However, these measures are unable to provide absolute assurance. We therefore do not guarantee that Dapper and our databases shall be immune from any wrongdoings and malfunctions. 

You may update, correct, or delete your profile information and preferences at any time by accessing your account preferences page on the Dapper website.  Please note that while your changes may be reflected promptly in active user databases, we may retain all information we collect for a variety of purposes, including backups and archiving, prevention of fraud and abuse, and analytics. Information we collect may be stored in archival form for up to two years, after which it will be de-identified or removed.

**IV.        _OUR COMMITMENT TO CHILDREN’S PRIVACY_**

Protecting the privacy of young children is especially important.  For that reason, we do not knowingly collect or maintain personally identifiable information from persons under 13 years-of-age, and no part of Dapper is not directed to persons under 13.  If you are under 13 years of age, then please do not use or access DAPPER at any time or in any manner.  If we learn that personally identifiable information of persons less than 13-years-of-age has been collected on Dapper without verifiable parental consent, then we will take the appropriate steps to delete this information.  If you are a parent or guardian and discover that your child under the age of 13 has obtained a Dapper account, then you may alert us at info@dapper.net and request that we delete that child’s personal information from our systems.
